Lucas Camponogara Viera

(+886) 0979 235 851

■ monteirocamponogara@gmail.com

camponogaraviera

■ lucas-camponogara-viera-5319871b

Currently working with Machine/Deep Learning and design of circuit-based quantum processors for Superconducting Quantum Computing. My research interests are mainly in the field of circuit Quantum Electrodynamics and Machine Learning. Notwithstanding, I am always keen to learn about related engineering and technology trends straddling multiple disciplines to enhance research skills and sharpen communication. My work experience include machine learning applied to image processing, computer vision and natural language processing, as well as software development for Bluetooth communication.

Education

National Taiwan Normal University - NTNU

Taipei, Taiwan

• PHD DEGREE IN ELECTRO-OPTICAL ENGINEERING, FOCUS ON QUANTUM COMPUTING

2020 - 2023 (Exp.)

• SUBJECT: DESIGN OF TRANSMON-BASED PROCESSORS FOR SUPERCONDUCTING QUANTUM COMPUTING

Federal University of Santa Maria - UFSM

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

• B.Sc. DEGREE IN CONTROL AND AUTOMATION ENGINEERING (INCOMPLETE)

2017 - 2018

 $\bullet \ \ \mathsf{COMPLETED} \ \mathsf{180} \ \mathsf{CREDITS} \ \mathsf{OF} \ \mathsf{COMPLEMENTARY} \ \mathsf{COURSEWORK} \ \mathsf{IN} \ \mathsf{COMPUTER} \ \mathsf{SCIENCE} \ \big(\mathsf{MACHINE}/\mathsf{DEEP} \ \mathsf{LEARNING}\big)$

• **Avg**: 8.04/10

Federal University of Santa Maria - UFSM

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

• M.Sc. DEGREE IN PHYSICS, FOCUS ON QUANTUM INFORMATION

2015 - 2017

• THESIS: DISTRIBUTION AND QUANTUM COHERENCE MANIPULATION IN MULTI-QUDIT SYSTEMS

Avg: 7.7/10

Federal University of Santa Maria - UFSM

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

• B.Sc. DEGREE IN PHYSICS, FOCUS ON QUANTUM ELECTRODYNAMICS

2011 – 2015

• THESIS: DIMENSIONAL ASPECTS OF PHOTON MASS IN QUANTUM ELECTRODYNAMICS

• Avg: 7.59/10

Professional Experience _____

Research Internship in Machine Learning Engineering

INSTITUTION: NATIONAL TAIWAN NORMAL UNIVERSITY (NTNU) - TAIPEI, TAIWAN

Taipei, Taiwan, Sept. 2019 - Feb. 2020

• **Subject:** The internship consisted of the development of a Generative Adversarial Network (GAN) with Python, Keras and TensorFlow for the purpose of image deblurring.

Software Engineer

COMPANY: NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF SPATIAL RESEARCH (INPE) - SANTA MARIA, RS, BRAZIL

Brazil, July 2017 – January 2019

• **Subject:** The project consisted of the development of a GUI based automation software in python for research data acquisition through a secure Bluetooth Communication Client-Server Channel.

Awards

RoboWeek Challenge

Federal University of Rio Grande, RS,

Brazil

2018 2018

Publications

L. V. Camponogara, "Distribution and Quantum Coherence Manipulation in Multi-Qudit Systems," M.S. Thesis, Ctr. of Nat. and Exct. Sciences., UFSM Univ., Santa Maria, RS, 2017.

L. V. Camponogara, "Dimensional Aspects of Photon Mass in Quantum Electrodynamics," B.S. Thesis, Ctr. of Nat. and Exct. Sciences., UFSM Univ., Santa Maria, RS, 2014.

Viera, L. C.; Muralikrishna, P.; Schuch, N. J.; Makita, K., "Study of Ionospheric Plasma in the South Atlantic Geomagnetic Anomaly Region," INPE/CNPq 114397/2011-2, 2012.

Technical Production

Baseline Architectures for Convolutional Denoising Autoencoder

Taipei, Taiwan

 DESCRIPTION: MACHINE LEARNING ARCHITECTURE FOR IMAGE DENOISING WITH AUTOENCODER NEURAL NETWORK DEVELOPED IN PYTHON USING KERAS AND TENSORFLOW.

2020

HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/AUTOENCODER/

Autoencoder - A Comprehensive Guide

Taipei, Taiwan

• DESCRIPTION: INVITED TALK ON DEEP LEARNING (2H).

 $\bullet \ \ \, \text{HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/INVITEDTALK/}$

DESCRIPTION: A PYTHON IMPLEMENTATION OF EVANS, E. A., AND R. SKALAK (1980) RED BLOOD CELL MODEL FOR 2019 THE PURPOSE OF HOLOGRAPHIC TOMOGRAPHY. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/RED-BLOOD-CELL-3D-SURFACE/ **Generator Network for an Image Deblurring GAN Architecture** Taipei, Taiwan DESCRIPTION: MACHINE LEARNING ARCHITECTURE FOR IMAGE DEBI LIRRING WITH A GENERATIVE ADVERSARIAL NET-2019 WORK (GAN) FRAMEWORK DEVELOPED IN PYTHON USING KERAS AND TENSORFLOW. • HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/GAN/ **Logistic Regression Based Facial Expression Recognition** Santa Maria, RS, Brazil · DESCRIPTION: MACHINE LEARNING ALGORITHM FOR CLASSIFYING HUMAN FACIAL EXPRESSIONS DEVELOPED IN 2018 PYTHON USING SCIKIT-LEARN. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/LOGISTICREGRESSION/ Kinematic Motion Algorithm for a TurtleBot in a Gazebo Environment Rio Grande, RS, Brazil AWARD: SECOND PLACE MEDAL AWARDED FROM A 24H ROBOTICS COMPETITION (ROBOWEEK) AT THE FEDERAL UNI-2018 VERSITY OF RIO GRANDE. DESCRIPTION: MOTION ALGORITHM DEVELOPED IN C++ FOR A GAZEBO SIMULATOR. • HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/ROBOWEEK-CHALLENGE/ Sentiment Analysis using LSTM and Word2Vec Santa Maria, RS, Brazil DESCRIPTION: MACHINE LEARNING ALGORITHM WITH LSTM AND WORD2VEC DEVELOPED IN PYTHON USING KERAS 2018 AND TENSORFLOW FOR INSIGHTFUL TEXT ANALYSIS ON ATTITUDE SENTIMENT EXPRESSED IN A BLOCK OF TEXT. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING Autonomous Software for data Acquisition via a Secure Bluetooth Santa Maria, RS, Brazil **Communication Client-Server Channel** · DESCRIPTION: GUI AUTOMATION SOFTWARE DEVELOPED IN PYTHON WITH BLUETOOTH COMMUNICATION FOR SEN-2017 SOR DATA ACQUISITION. PLATFORM: WINDOWS • HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/BLUETOOTH-COMMUNICATION/ **Snake Game - MVC Standard** Santa Maria, RS, Brazil DESCRIPTION: SNAKE GAME WITH AN INTERACTIVE MENU DEVELOPED IN PYTHON WITH PYGAME ENGINE AND MVC 2017 STANDARD. PLATFORM: DESKTOP

Taipei, Taiwan

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

2017

Technical Skills _

Red Blood Cell 3D-Surface Triangulation

- Programming Languages: Python, MATLAB, C, HTML5, CSS.
- Frameworks and Libraries: Tensorflow, Keras, scikit-learn, Qiskit, Cirq, sympy, Pygame, OpenCV.
- Others: Git, Linux, Android Studio, LATEX.

https://camponogaraviera.github.io/Game-Development/
Supervised Teaching in Quantum Mechanics

• INSTITUTION: FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF SANTA MARIA

Languages

WORKLOAD: 15H

• Portuguese (Native); English (ILR Level 4); Spanish (Professional working prof.); German (Elementary prof.); Chinese (Elementary prof.).

Will be pleased to provide references upon request.